A single hospitalization can destroy your entire
investment portfolio,
so a health insurance policy is the
mainstay of your investment portfolio.
So, you
cannot purchase any health insurance policy without comparison.
Purchasing a health insurance policy after comparison
is a very difficult task because in our country,
33 general insurance companies
sell health insurance plans and five
stand-alone health insurance companies
send health insurance plans. These
40 health insurance companies have
around 250 to 300 health
insurance plans available. Now,
choosing one health insurance plan from these 300 and
purchasing it is a difficult task,
but after watching this video of mine,
your problem is going to be completely solved.
Today, I have brought
before you a comparison of four health insurance plans, out of which
two are new health
insurance companies, whose two new health
insurance plans I have brought before you,
but neither are these insurance companies
nor are their plans new.
I have brought these insurance plans for the first time on our channel, so stay tuned.
In this video of mine, till the end and if you have
not yet subscribed to the insurance service, then
subscribe to it now and
also press the bell icon so that you
get notifications of all my videos.
[Music]
Before starting the video, I would
like to give you my disclaimer that this
video is not sponsored by any insurance company. In
fact, none of our videos are
sponsored by any insurance company. The
objective of our videos is to make
you aware about insurance, make you
aware about insurance plans and to keep
you updated about all the updates that come in insurance. Also,
our objective is to compare all the
health insurance plans and life insurance
plans available in the market and
bring them in front of you so that you
can choose the best health insurance and best life insurance policy for yourself and your family. So, Fox, let's start
today's video with a comparison of four health insurance
plans, in which two
new health insurance plans have been added, in
which the first is ICICI Lombard's
Mass Product Plan. ICICI Lombard
is fundamentally a strong company with a turnover of Rs. 82000
crore.  Its net worth is Rs. 90.
Talking about the claim settlement ratio,
its claim settlement ratio is 99.
Its solvency is 2.5, which means that against a liability of Rs. 1, it has
Rs. 1000000 available. It has an
online claim settlement process with 15000 network hospitals, which
means that
you can make reimbursement claims online. Let's
talk about Money Pal
Cigna, which is the second health insurance
plan I have added here. It is a very good
company, it is a new company, this company has been in existence for the last five years.
Its plan is Life Time
Health Plan. If I talk about the claim
settlement ratio, its
claim settlement ratio is Rs. 90. Its
claim ratio is 79 and its solvency is 1.67, which
means it is
Rs. 1000000
plus and the total worth of the company is currently Rs.
2000 crore. If we talk about  Regarding
reimbursement claim process, it will be
completely online.
I have linked these two insurance companies with
hdfcergo.com. The
settlement ratio is at 99.
Its net worth is Rs. 3800 crore. The fundamentals of this company are very
strong. It is the third largest general
insurance company in our country.
Its in-card claim ratio is 79 and its
solvency is 1.85, which means against Rs. 1, it has
Rs. 15,00,000
network hospitals.
Talking about nb, nb
Rio 2.0 is a very famous plan. It is a
Revolution Health Insurance Plan.
It has 11,000 plus network hospitals. Its
claim process is also online.
You
can get your claim processed by going to the link and uploading all the documents. 54  It has an income
claim ratio of 1.99, a
claim settlement ratio of 91, and a
solvency ratio of 1.77, meaning it has options of ₹10,00,000. If
we look at the options of ₹10,00,000, then in ADAC, Go
Optima Secure, options are available for sums of ₹5 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20
lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh, and ₹1 crore.
If we talk about Moneypal Cigna, Moneypal
Cigna's Life Time Health Plan is a higher sum
assured segment plan. It has options for sum assured of ₹50
lakh, 75 lakh, ₹1 crore, 6 crore, 2 crore,
meaning it will have a
minimum sum assured of ₹1 lakh.
If we talk about the III Lord Max product,
it is also a high sum assured segment plan.
If you wish to take a sum assured of ₹1 crore or more, then
this
plan is perfectly suitable for you. It is best from ₹1 crore
to  They have time limit options up to ₹ crore
and like Ekko General, they have
also given an option of unlimited time limit
in it. Unlimited means that
you can use any amount of time limit
after going to the hospital and after going for N number of claims. At the
same time,
Niva BPA Rish 2.2 age will be normal 5 lakh, 75 lakh, 10
lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh
and time limit options up to ₹ crore will be
available with them. Talking about the entry age,
ADFC Optima Secure will
have 18 to 65 and dependent child from 91
days to 25 years. Same will be in Money Pal Cigna,
18 to 65 and from 91 days to
25 years. At the same time, Niva BPA Rish
2.0 says that from 18 years to 65 years, then
I will call him Age of an Adult.  I will consider it but
I will also consider the dependent child from 91 days to
30 years. This company is going to purchase this policy
in ICICI Lombard. A person from 6 years to
65 years can purchase this policy. The
policy tenure in all the four policies is
for 1 year, 2 years and 3 years. Regarding the
variants of all these four policies, there are
three variants in Optima Secure - Optima Secure Global
and Global Plus. If you opt for Global and Global
Plus, then you
can get its treatment done even outside India. There is
no variant in Money Pal Signal Life Time, it is a single policy. There will
be four variants in n v rio 2.0 - Titanium,
Platinum, Bronze and Gold. There will be two variants in ICICI Lombard -
Classic and Premier.
Their features are going to change according to their variants.
Talking about family size, this policy will be available
for hdfcergo.com Max product 2 adults and 3 kit. There will be
no capping on room net in ADAC Go, in Manipal
Signal and n v rio 2.0  But
in the IIC Lord Max product,
any room can be taken except the Suite Room.
Talking about other features, there
is no capping of ICU and ICCU. There is no co-
payment in all the four policies.
Pre and
post hospitalization is a very important
part in all the four policies because there are a
lot of expenses before going to the hospital and there are a
lot of expenses even after coming back from the hospital.
In all the four policies, up to 60 days pre
hospitalization and 180 days post
hospitalization claim can be
taken. Day care treatment:
Up to 60 days post hospitalization cover is available in all the four policies. All day
care is covered. Talking about modern treatment, all
modern treatments are covered in HDFC Bank, Moneypal Cigna and IIC Labad. There is
no capping.
However, in NB Rio 2.0, there is a capping of
₹1 lakh on robotic surgeries in modern treatment.
E-consultation will
not be available in SDAC Ergo Optima Secure. Tele-consultation will not be available
in Manipal Cigna.  Consultation can be
taken as an added rider.
Unlimited teleconsultation can be taken in nBP 2.0 and
unlimited teleconsultation can also be taken in III Lord Max product.
Talking about restoration, it is a
very important part
in today's health insurance policy because
restoration is useful when there are
multiple hospitalizations for a single
disease or for different diseases
in a single year. In ADAC Ergo,
unlimited restoration can be taken for the same illness from the same person by paying % extra premium.
Whereas, unlimited restoration is available in Money Pal Signal Life
Time Health Plan
but it will be
for unrelated illnesses.
You will not get the facility of unlimited restoration on the same illness.
In nB, unlimited restoration will be for the
same person for the same illness and
in IC Lord Max product, restoration will be one
time, up to 100% and for the
same person only once in a year.  This facility can also be availed for the same illness.
Talking about road ambulance, ADAC Ar,
Manipal Cigna and Niva b Rio 2.0 offer road
ambulance up to ₹10 lakh. There is
no capping. However, in ICICI Lord
Max product, hospitalization will be capped at ₹1000000.
Talking about air ambulance,
hospitalization can be availed at ₹1 lakh in ADFC.
In Manipal, one will have to take add-on cover for hospitalization up to ₹10
lakh. Also,
in Niva Bupa, hospitalization up to ₹1 lakh.
We can avail air ambulance.
In ICICI Lord Max product, we have
provided this cover in the Premier category. There is no
capping or limit. Talking about no claim
bonus, ADAC Argo has
Plus Benefit which is not a no claim bonus.
Plus Benefit, whether there is a claim or
not, your time
limit will increase every year by 50%, going up to a maximum of 100%.
Because it is not a no claim bonus,
then it will not be reduced in case of a claim.
Money Pal Signa has a very good no
claim bonus. It can also be called a cumulative bonus. It is called a
loyalty bonus. By the way, these people call
it 15% yearly. Your time limit will increase
and it will increase for life time even if there is a
claim in the policy or even if there is
no claim. That is, if you have a
policy of ₹1 lakh, then in it a no claim bonus of ₹1 lakh will
increase every year and will increase till life time. So, it is going to
beat inflation as well. Let's
talk about Niva Bappa,
there is Booster Plus, whatever
remaining time you have left, that is Accumatika.
So, in all the four policies, home care, domestic
treatment up to that time will be covered. The
waiting period of PD means pre-
existing
[Music]
In Lord Max product,
pre-existing cover can be taken after 48 months.
Now let us talk about annual health plan. It is a very important part of annual health plan.
Health checkup because by getting annual health checkup done once or twice a year,
we come to know timely that cholesterol is increasing,
sugar is increasing, then we
take timely rectify steps for it,
get treatment for it and the disease is
saved from becoming chronic. So, if we talk about ADAC Ergo
Optima Secure, then we can claim
annual health checkup of ₹5000000 on reimbursement basis,
maximum limit is
₹15000000 by
going to their network hospitals, that is, whatever they do will be
on cashless basis. In Niva BAP Rish 2.2 also, ₹500
per lakh has been kept, maximum limit will
be ₹10000 but it will be only on cashless basis.
This claim will not be available in reimbursement.
You will have to book annual health checkup by going to their app
and after that you can get
annual health checkup done, you can also get it done through home visit,
you can also get it done by going to the centre.
ICSA  This cover is available in Lombard
but it will be with add-on cover. There will be
listed tests and you can get it done on cashless basis.
Alternative treatment means Ayurvedic
treatment, Homeopathic treatment, Siddha
Unani. All such treatments are
called alternative treatment.
Nowadays, it is a trend and is very effective. Alternative treatment is available
in many diseases.
Up to
sum cover is available in all the four policies. No limit or conditions have been
kept. Now let us talk about maternity
cover. It is an event which is needed in youngsters
and this event comes in everyone's life sometime or the other.
This facility will not be available in ADFC Ergo.
With add-on cover in Money Pal Cigna, you can take
maternity cover up to ₹1 lakh for two deliveries.
Its waiting period will be 3 years.
N B and I Se Loba Mas product and
Rio 2.0 will not have maternity cover. There are
four lists of consumables. NR1 has four
lists - 1, 2, 3, 4.  There are at least 700 to
800 such items which insurance
companies do not cover, but
in ADAC Optima Secure, all these items are
covered. No additional
charge will be taken for them, it is an inbuilt cover in the policy, in
this way, a zero cost
policy will be available. In Manpal Cigna, you
can take an add-on shield of consumer benefits, then
your consumer benefits will be covered,
whereas in Niva Bappa, if you add Safeguard Plus, then
your consumer benefits will be covered in it.
If you opt for Premier in ICI Lord Max product, then
Premier will have consumer in-built cover. Let's
talk about wellness program.
In wellness program, insurance companies
say that you should keep yourself healthy,
you should exercise regularly, go for regular walks,
then we will incentivize you, will
reduce your premium, will give you a discount in the premium.
ADAC is
not providing this facility, but there
is a loyalty discount in Manpal Cigna, but
this wellness program is not there here, but  There
is a loyalty discount. After 4 years, you will get a guaranteed
discount of 5% on your premium
and after 8 years, you will
get a guaranteed discount of 10%
and you will get this discount for life time
but in nb, if you walk some steps per day and
keep yourself healthy, then you
can get a discount of up to 30%.
In the Load Max product, you will have to take this
add-on cover. You will get a
discount of up to 30% in it. Deducted means
share some amount from your pocket
and your premium will reduce to a great extent.
So let me talk about
hdfc000000 You can take a deductible of 1 lakh, 2 lakh and 3 lakh. There will be
no deductible in Money Pal Cigna. In nb r 2.0, a discount of up to 40% can be availed by
taking a deductible of 20000, 30000, 50000 and ₹1 lakh. The
option of deductible will not be available in the Load Max product. So, let us now talk about
these.  Regarding the add-on covers of all the four plans
and what are the special features in it, then
ADAC G Optima Secure
has Secure Benefit, that is, buy one get one
free of ₹1 lakh. If you
take a plan, then you will get a plan of ₹1 lakh from day one, that is, you will get
₹1 lakh free with ₹10 lakh, ₹
50 lakh
free with ₹50 lakh. Global and Global Plus are
variants in this. If you opt for Global or Global
Plus, then the premium will
increase slightly, it will increase significantly, but you
can get treatment even after going outside India. It has inbuilt consumer benefits.
As I told you, if we talk about Money Pal Cigna, then it has
many add-ons
and many special features. Here
you can take Global cover.
27 major illnesses are covered in Global cover. Along with this,
you can also take cover for HIV AIDS Mental Care Global and Pre and Post in Global. There is
also an option of premium waiver
if the proposer dies accidentally
or has any critical condition.  If there is an illness, the
premium for one year will be waived.
Travel vaccination is also covered in this plan.
In many countries, some vaccinations are mandatory and one has to get them done before going there.
Their cover is
provided in this plan. Cash benefit is provided in
case of accident, chemotherapy or any major
illness, a lump sum cash will be given.
There is also a women's special plan
for women. Many tests are covered.
Many screenings are covered, such as
overutilization.
Your premium will not increase.
Safeguard Plus has been added as an add-on rider.
If you add Safeguard Plus,
your consumable items will be covered.
Also,
your sum will be increased according to inflation and
your booster will not be impacted on claims up to ₹1 lakh.
Hospital cash and personal
accident are covered as an add-on.
You can take critical illness as an add-on cover. There
is a disease management rider if you
opt for it. Diabetes and hypertension are also covered.  It is
covered from day one. IC
Lumbard has worldwide cover. If you
take the premier premium variant,
then you will be given worldwide cover and
can take air ambulance cover. There is an option for
pre-exit illness i.e.
you can also reduce your premium by taking your pre-existing illness cover of 48 months.
So all these features are
given in these policies. Now I will talk about the
premium because without premium
any plan comparison will be completely incomplete
because only the premium will tell how heavy
this plan is going to be on my pocket or your pocket,
whether
these plans come in my budget. So
I have taken a cover of ₹ 1 lakh for HDFC Insurance and Optima Secure.
Here I have taken ₹ 1 lakh
because here one is free with one.
20 lakh means you will get a cover of 40 lakh from day one. I have
taken an age of 40 years and
I have taken a family size of two adults and two kits and
along with this, the
premium will be 41000 530 on Delhi NCR address and in this  Your
consumables will be covered in build Money Pal
Cigna's lifetime plan of ₹1 crore
for the same age group will cost ₹42000 for Delhi NCR, it is
very economical n be 2.2
Here I have taken ₹50 lakh, when the
comparison is being done then
we will compare it with almost the same sum shot, the
premium will come out to be ₹5799
after adding SE and Plus, the Lord Max product has a
cover of ₹1 crore which is the minimum, there are two
variants, one is Classic and the other
is Premier, in Classic you will have to pay ₹
43,557 with a pre-assisting waiting period of two years,
this is also very economical and
in Premier you will have to
pay only ₹2883, this plan is also very
economical, so how did you like this
plan, after seeing this comparison, it must have become
very easy for you to
compare any plan, to
choose any plan, stay safe and healthy for yourself and your family
Whatever questions or queries you have related to these plans,
I will give them all to you in my comment box.
You can also call me or mail me. I will meet
you as always.
Next Saturday I will bring the next video. Till then
Jai Hind Jai Bharat.